Finding Aid for the Peter H. Prince Papers MS.2921
University of Tennessee Libraries, Special Collections
Peter H. Prince Papers
1770-2006
MS.2921
University of Tennessee Libraries, Special Collections
139.75 Linear feet
The bulk of this collection is composed of photographs, newspaper clippings, computer printouts, xerox copies, floppy disks, correspondence, and reference publications documenting Peter Hayden Pete Prince's research into the history of his family and of the Great Smoky Mountains both before and after the Great Smoky Mountains National Park was formed. Other materials document Prince's personal life (including his two fiancees, his work with cerebral palsy patients, his struggle to find housing, and the injuries he sustained in a car accident) from approximately 1990 to his death in 2006.
Prince, Pete, 1935-
Conditions Governing Access
Colletions are stored offsite, and a minimum of 24 hours is needed to retrieve these items for use. Researchers interested in consulting any of the collections are advised to contact Special Collections at special@utk.edu.
Acquisition Note
Pete Prince's sons formally donated this collection to the University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Special Collections in April of 2006. Prince had arranged to deposit these papers at the Library before his death.
Biographical/Historical Note
Hayden Peter Prince (who legally changed his name to Peter Hayden Prince on July 24, 1962) was born on May 31, 1935 in Sewanee, Tennessee to Hayden Alton and Minnie Agnes (Moinette) Prince. Orphaned in 1946, Prince spent several years among relatives in Tennessee and Florida before learning printing at the Tennessee Prepatory School in Nashville between 1949 and 1954. Although he never graduated from college, Prince attended the George Peabody College for Teachers (1954-1958) and the University of Tennessee's College of Journalism (1958-1959), where he gained considerable journalistic experience.
In 1959, Prince hitchhiked to McMinnville, Tennessee, to work as the news editor for the Southern Standard. In 1960, Prince left the Standard to become a reporter/photographer for the Knoxville News-Sentinel. He stayed with the Sentinel until becoming the director of public relations for St. Mary's Memorial Hospital in 1966. He returned to journalism in 1968, this time as the associate publisher and managing editor of the Clinton Courier-News. In 1971, he took a position as the executive editor of the Citizen Tribune, where he remained until suffering a severe manic depressive episode 1985. Prince also served as a national board member of the Society of Professional Journalists (1977-1984), as a nominating juror for the Pulitzer Prize (1981-1982), as a charter member of the Hamblen County Historical Society (1978), and as a sexton and administrative board committeeman for the First United Methodist Church.
As a result of his mental illness, Prince was legally declared disabled, left journalism permanently, and returned to the research he had begun while writing Prince Family Prince: the Story of 1400 Princes Across America (1982). He quickly became fascinated with the history of the Great Smoky Mountains and devoted considerable energy to researching 251 towns that were destroyed in order to create the Great Smoky Mountains National Park. He intended to publish his findings as a 10-volume set entitled Ghost Towns of the Great Smokies, but had not completed the first book (dealing with Western North Carolina) at the time of his death.
Toward the end of his life, Prince was increasingly tormented by severe paranoia. In the late 1990s, he became convinced that an unidentified person or persons were attempting to steal his photographs and/or research. By the early 2000s, this paranoia had evolved to include a belief that these tormentors meant to kill him. Prince was particularly terrified of fire, and filed frequent complaints with his apartment complex about obstructions that he believed would trap him and others in the building, causing them to burn to death. This paranoia became particularly obvious after he was evicted on unrelated grounds in 2003 and struggled to find new housing. In the same year, Prince was injured in a car accident in Maryville. He never recovered fully, and the psychological ramifications of these injuries contributed significantly to his death on April 10, 2006. Prince is buried beside his mother in Sewanee, Tennessee.
Prince married Millicent Norma Ruth Melhorn (who legally changed her name from Norma Ruth Melhorn on July 24, 1962) on August 11, 1962 at the Church Street United Methodist Church in Knoxville, Tennessee. The couple had three sons: Michael Hayden, Daniel Melhorn, and Jonathan Moinette. In 1990, Prince divorced his wife in order to marry Peggye Owens Adams. For unknown reasons, this marriage never took place. In 2006, Prince became engaged to childhood sweetheart Aliese Owens Griffin, but the pair were not married before Prince's death.
Scope and Contents Note
Series I: Research Files, 1770-2006 houses the files that Prince created while researching own family history and the history of the Great Smoky Mountains. The bulk of the research (housed in Sub-Series B through Sub-Series I) is devoted to the Smokies and includes photocopies of books and articles, correspondence with libraries and other researchers, printouts of Internet sites, notes, and other materials. Sub-Series J houses Prince's extensive collection of photographs showing people and places in the Smoky Mountains. The vast majority of these images are copies of originals held at the Blount County Public Library, the University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Special Collections, the Tennessee Valley Authority (TVA) Library, and the North Carolina State Library and Archives. Some, however, are copies of images owned by private citizens whose families originated in the area that the Great Smoky Mountains National Park now occupies. Prince himself took several while working for the Knoxville News-Sentinel. Finally, this series includes maps showing many of the locations that Prince was researching and publications that Prince kept for reference purposes.
Researchers should note that the vast majority of the cemeteries that Prince takes credit for discovering were found by dowsing. Dowsing has traditionally been used to locate water on open ground, but some dowsers believe that it can also find such lost objects as graves, railroads, and buildings. According to this theory, the dowser's rods will cross as he passes over the location previously occupied by the item in question and uncross when he moves away from it. Unfortunately, this method is not completely accurate, as Prince himself discovered when two experts (one professional and one lay) found no evidence of burials at a site that Prince claimed contained the remains of 37 Caucasians, 14 slaves, and 12 Union soldiers. Additionally, Prince assumes race and culture based on the orientation of the grave; thus, whites are buried facing east, slaves are buried facing south, and Cherokee (Prince does not claim to have discovered graves created by other tribes) are buried in the fetal position.
Additionally, Prince occasionally references research that is not housed in this collection. The two most prominent examples of this phenomenon are interviews that Prince conducted with people who had lived in some of the towns that he was researching and Prince's daily journal, which he kept from the 1950s to 2006.
Series II: Publications, 1890-2005 houses drafts and materials that Prince had set aside to write Prince Family Prince and Ghost Towns of the Great Smokies. The majority of the drafts pertain to Ghost Towns and were printed from floppy disks that Prince had assembled. The smaller articles were apparently meant to be paired with images housed in Sub-Series J of Series I and published as a set.
Series III: Personal Papers, 1980-2006 includes materials showing the later portion of Prince's personal life. Much of it documents Prince's gradual slide into depression and paranoia, particularly the lawsuits Prince intended to file against his apartment complex (which he claimed had endangered his life and evicted him unfairly), the Maryville Housing Board (which he claimed had wrongfully denied him housing at Broadway Towers), and Habitat for Humanity (which he claimed had improperly dismissed him from their program and so cheated him out of a home). This series also houses materials documenting the injuries that Prince sustained in his car accident, the lawsuit that Prince wanted to file against the two drivers who had hit him, and Prince's gradual conclusion that his injuries would eventually kill him.
Arrangement
This collection consists of ninety-seven boxes divided into four series:
Series I: Research Files, 1770-2006
Sub-Series A: Prince Family Genealogical Research, 1770-2006
Sub-Series B: Blount County, Tennessee, 1813-1996
Sub-Series C: Sevier County, Tennessee, 1861-2005
Sub-Series D: Cocke County, Tennessee, 1810-2006 (bulk 1903-2006)
Sub-Series E: North Carolina, 1820-2005 (bulk 1880-2005)
Sub-Series F: Buncombe, Haywood, Macon, Jackson, and Swain Counties, North Carolina, 1945-2006 (bulk 1900-2006)
Sub-Series G: Southeastern Railroads, 1858-2005 (bulk circa 1909-2005)
Sub-Series H: Great Smoky Mountains Genealogical Research, 1952-2003 (bulk 1872-1996)
Sub-Series I: Other Research Files, 1872-2001
Sub-Series J: Photographs, 1838-2006 (bulk 1884-2005)
Sub-Series K: Maps, 1883-2005
Sub-Series L: Reference Publications, 1883-2006 (bulk 1945-2006)
Series II: Publications, 1890-2005
Sub-Series A: Prince Family Prince, 1890-2005
Sub-Series B: Ghost Towns of the Great Smokies, 1892-2005
Sub-Series C: Drafts, 1944-2003 (bulk 1987-2003)
Series III: Personal Papers, 1980-2006
Sub-Series A: Cerebral Palsy Advocacy, 1997-2005
Sub-Series B: Housing, 1980-2005 (bulk 2002-2005)
Sub-Series C: Car Accident and Lawsuit, 2003-2006 (bulk 2004-2005)
Sub-Series D: Profile Sheets, 1992-2006
Sub-Series E: Photographs, 1993-2006
Sub-Series F: Other Papers, 1994-2006
Series IV: Oversized and Other Materials, 1833-2006
Separated Materials
Numerous published works donated with this collection have been removed and cataloged into the University of Tennessee's Rare Books Collection.
Subjects
Prince family; Cemeteries -- Southern States.; Cherokee Indians -- Southern States.; Dowsing.; Great Smoky Mountains (N.C. and Tenn.) -- History.; Great Smoky Mountains (N.C. and Tenn.) -- Pictorial works.; Great Smoky Mountains National Park (N.C. and Tenn.) -- History.; Great Smoky Mountains National Park (N.C. and Tenn.) -- Pictorial works.; Southern States -- Genealogy.; Southern States -- Pictorial works.; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865.
Container List
- Research Files, 1770-2006; I
  - Prince Family Genealogical Research, 1770-2006; A
    - Amstutz Family Research, 1823-1996 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Amstutz Genealogy, 1823-1997; (1 of 2); [Oversized Materials Removed to Box 58, Folder 1] (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Amstutz Genealogy, 1823-1997; (2 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Matthew Lee Clark, 2003-2005 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Clark Genealogy, 1864-2004; (1 of 4) (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Clark Genealogy, 1864-2004; (2 of 4) (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Clark Genealogy, 1864-2004; (3 of 4) (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Clark Genealogy, 1864-2004; (4 of 4) (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Eskridge Genealogy, 1820-1985; (1 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Eskridge Genealogy, 1820-1985; (2 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Thomas J. Forney (for whom Forney's Creek Township, North Carolina, is named), 1820-2005; (1 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Thomas J. Forney (for whom Forney's Creek Township, North Carolina, is named), 1820-2005; (2 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Thomas J. Forney (for whom Forney's Creek Township, North Carolina, is named), 1820-2005; (3 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Melhorn-Hamby Genealogy, 1985-2005 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Melhorn-Hamby Genealogy, 1814-1983; (1 of 4) (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Melhorn-Hamby Genealogy, 1814-1983; (2 of 4) (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Melhorn-Hamby Genealogy, 1814-1983; (3 of 4) (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Melhorn-Hamby Genealogy, 1814-1983; (4 of 4); [Oversized Materials Removed to Box 59, Folder 1] (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Melhorn-Hamby Genealogy, 1871-2000; (1 of 2); [Oversized Materials Removed to Box 59, Folder 2] (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Melhorn-Hamby Genealogy, 1871-2000; (2 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Moinette Genealogy, 1925-2000; [Oversized Material Removed to Box 58, Folder 2] (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Moinette Genealogy, 1981-2000 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Elizabeth Betty Moinette Solomon, 1880-1984 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Felicia Moinette Bligh, 1906-2000; [Oversized Material Removed to Box 59, Folder 3] (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Henry Moinette and William Bryant, 1899-2005; [Oversized Material Removed to Box 59, Folder 4] (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Peter Moinette Sr. (Union Soldier), 1870-1981; (1 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Peter Moinette Sr. (Union Soldier), 1870-1981; (2 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Peter Moinette Sr. (Union Soldier), 1870-1981; (3 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Thomas Moinette and Cleo Snell, 1830-1985 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Prince Genealogy, 1790-1984; (1 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Prince Genealogy, 1790-1984; (2 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Prince Genealogy, 1790-1984; (3 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Pete Prince Ancestor Charts, 1790-1984; (1 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Pete Prince Ancestor Charts, 1790-1984; (2 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Prince Confederate Soldiers, 1861-1983 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Prince Confederate Soldiers, 1861-1985; (1 of 2); [Oversized Materials Removed to Box 59, Folder 5] (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Prince Confederate Soldiers, 1861-1985; (2 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Prince Union Soldiers, Volume I, 1861-1989; (1 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Prince Union Soldiers, Volume I, 1861-1989; (2 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Prince Union Soldiers, Volume I, 1861-1989; (3 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Prince Union Soldiers, Volume II, 1863-1984; (1 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Prince Union Soldiers, Volume II, 1863-1984; (2 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Prince Union Soldiers, Volume II, 1863-1984; (3 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Edward Prince of Virginia, 1982-1985 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Hardy Prince Genealogy, 1830-1983 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - North Carolina Princes, 1788-1989 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Polk County Princes, 1770-2001; (1 of 2); [Oversized Items Removed to Box 59, Folder 6] (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Polk County Princes, 1770-2001; (2 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Raus Princes, 1886-1996 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Ron Prince Letters, 1968-2003 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - William Smith Letters (Revolutionary War Soldier), 1964-1986 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Dr. Clark Whittier Lands, 1882-1991 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Young Genealogy, 1870-1986; (1 of 2); [Oversized Materials Removed to Box 59, Folder 7] (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Young Genealogy, 1870-1986; (1 of 2); [Oversized Materials Removed to Box 59, Folder 7] (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Loose Genealogical Material, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Blank Genealogical Forms, undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Andrews Bald, North Carolina, Volume I, 1886-2006; (1 of 3); [Oversized Materials Removed to Box 90, Folder 4] (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Andrews Bald, North Carolina, Volume I, 1886-2006; (2 of 3) (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Andrews Bald, North Carolina, Volume I, 1886-2006; (3 of 3) (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Andrews Bald, North Carolina, Volume II, 1896-2005; (1 of 3) (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Andrews Bald, North Carolina, Volume II, 1896-2005; (2 of 3) (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Andrews Bald, North Carolina, Volume II, 1896-2005; (3 of 3) (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Tennessee River Baptist Association, 1896-1993 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Blount County, Tennessee, 1813-1996; B
    - Understanding Dowsing with Pete Prince (DVD), 2006 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Smokies Guide, 2005-2006; [Oversized Material Removed to Box 59, Folder 8] (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - The Blount Journal, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Loose Material Regarding Blount County and GSMNP, 1992-2005; [Oversized Materials Removed to Box 59, Folder 9] (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - ISBN for Book Publishing, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Calderwood, Tenn., 1998 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Maryville-Alcoa Times Bicentennial Edition, 1976 February 27; [Oversized Materials Removed to Box 59, Folder 10] (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Pucsage noted on Tennessee River (Blount County), 2004 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Kirkland Bushwhackers vicious, bloody outlaws; Civil War deserters, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Sultana Steamboat Explosion, 1998-2005 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Alcoa, 1947-1976 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Term Smoky Mountains first used, 1934-2001 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Maryville, Tenn., 1987-2000 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Overmountain Men at the Battle of Kings Mountain, 2003-2004 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - William Bartram (American Naturalist), 2005 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Hiram C. Wilburn (first GSMNP unofficial historian), 1953-1967 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Map of the Rockford-Lakemont (Tennessee) area, undated (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Tennessee (Cherokee Name), 1975 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Logging (America's most dangerous occupation), 2004 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Pigeon River (named for the Passenger Pigeon), 2003 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Blount County Marriages in 1922, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - U. S. Highway 129, 1928-2000 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - U. S. 129 (Opened 1930 June 23), 2003 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Little Tennessee River, 2004-2005 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Waterfalls in Tennessee (compiled at UT Knoxville), 2004 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - U. S. 129 Dragon Area (South Blount County, Tenn.), 2004 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Source of Tennessee River (Rabun County, Ga.), 2003 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Pucsage Recognized as the Narrows of the Tennessee River, undated (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Tallassee Ford (now Calderwood) in the Civil War, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Blount County, Tenn.: History, 1957-1975 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Blount County, Tenn.: Fort Loudon, 1978-1998 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Blount County Public Library, 1836-1997 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Blount County, Tenn.: Wild Boar, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Cherokee Indian Towns: Calderwood, Tenn., 2003 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Cherokee Indian Towns: Cooper Camp Springs, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Cherokee Indian Towns: Tallassee, 1955-1975 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Cherokee Indian Towns: Cherokee Surrender Blount County Lands (1819), 1957 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Cherokee Indian Towns: Chilhowee, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Cherokee Indian Towns: Cherokee Migration (1819), 1975 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Cherokee Indian Towns: Unicoi Turnpike, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Georgia: Rabun Gap Short Line Railway, 2003-2004 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Georgia: Tallulah Falls Railroad, 1995-2004 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Slate Mines (est. 1886) on Abrams and Panther Creeks, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Parson's Turnpike (built 1829): Joshua Parson's early records, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Parson's Turnpike (built 1829): Parson Deeds Involving Turnpike, undated (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Parson's Turnpike (built 1829): History, 1847-2006 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Parson's Turnpike (built 1829): Calloway Turnpike, 1957-1975 (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Parson's Turnpike (built 1829): Foute Road, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - Parson's Turnpike (built 1829): Tallassee Ferry, 1975-2003 (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - Wilham: Shop Creek, 1984-1994 (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - Wilham: Tabcat Creek, 1935-2002 (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - Chilhowee: John Martin Lumber Railroad, 1989-2004 (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - Chilhowee: Montvale Springs, 1947-2004 (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - Chilhowee: History, 1897-2000 (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - Chilhowee: Chilhowee Indian Town, 1914-2001 (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - Chilhowee: Citico & Grand Forks Railroad, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - Chilhowee: Ghormley Family, 1956-1999 (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - Chilhowee: McMurray's Chapel, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - Chilhowee: Ghormley's Chapel/McMurray's Chapel, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 60)
    - Chilhowee: Lt. Henry Timberlake, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 61)
    - Chilhowee: David Smith's Store and Ferry, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 62)
    - Chilhowee: Tabcat School, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 63)
    - Chilhowee: Chilhowee School, undated (Box 4, Folder 64)
    - Chilhowee: Old Abram (Chief of Chilhowie), 1940-1993 (Box 4, Folder 65)
    - Chilhowee: Abram's Falls (Lower Chilhowee River), 1957 (Box 4, Folder 66)
    - Chilhowee: Thomas H. Boring, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 67)
    - Chilhowee: Joshua Parson's Mill, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 68)
    - Chilhowee: Chilhowee Spinning and Manufacturing Co., 1957 (Box 4, Folder 69)
    - Chilhowee: Wilham, 1957-1981 (Box 4, Folder 70)
    - Chilhowee: St. James' Episcopal Church, 1957-1998 (Box 4, Folder 71)
    - Chilhowee: Chilhowee Mountain (2451'), 1853-2001 (Box 4, Folder 72)
    - Chilhowee: Jones County and Governor Lean Jimmy Jones, 1957-2001 (Box 4, Folder 73)
    - Chilhowee: Flatboats on the Little Tennessee, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 74)
    - Chilhowee: Robert William James, 1957-1999 (Box 4, Folder 75)
    - Chilhowee: Howard, McGhee, and Jones Feud (1900), 1975-1997 (Box 4, Folder 76)
    - Chilhowee: Thomas Howard, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 77)
    - Chilhowee: Morton Butler Lumber Co., undated (Box 4, Folder 78)
    - Chilhowee: Parson's Turnpike Tollhouse (1829-1930), 1957-1992 (Box 4, Folder 79)
    - Abram's Creek: Carson's Iron Works, 1957-1991 (Box 4, Folder 80)
    - Abram's Creek: Tallassee, Tenn., 2004 (Box 4, Folder 81)
    - Abram's Creek: Tallassee Inn on the Little Tennessee River, 1929-2004 (Box 4, Folder 82)
    - Abram's Creek: Burchfield Cemetery (also Chestnut Flats), 1987 (Box 4, Folder 83)
    - Abram's Creek: Cane Creek Cemetery, 1957-1987 (Box 4, Folder 84)
    - Abram's Creek: Lone Grove, Buchannan, and :Laurel Twins Cemetery, 1987-1993 (Box 4, Folder 85)
    - Abram's Creek: Cooper-Whitehead Cemetery, 1987-996 (Box 4, Folder 86)
    - Abram's Creek: Boring Cemetery, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 87)
    - Abram's Creek: Chilhowee Cemetery, 1899-1995 (Box 4, Folder 88)
    - Abram's Creek: Panther Hill Cemetery, undated (Box 4, Folder 89)
    - Abram's Creek: Bas Shaw Cemetery, 1987-2003 (Box 4, Folder 90)
    - Abram's Creek: Stomping North Hughes Cemetery, 1980-1995 (Box 4, Folder 91)
    - Abram's Creek: Jason Maynard Cemetery, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 92)
    - Abram's Creek: Parson's Turnpike Indian Cemetery, 1987-2004 (Box 4, Folder 93)
    - Abram's Creek: Lucy J. Morton Cemetery, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 94)
    - Abram's Creek: Mitchell Branch Cemetery, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 95)
    - Abram's Creek: Tabcat Gap Cemetery, 1988-1995 (Box 4, Folder 96)
    - Abram's Creek: Henry (Doc) Gormley Mill, undated; [Folder Found Empty] (Box 4, Folder 97)
    - Richwood: Boy Boring Grist Mill, undated; [Folder Found Empty] (Box 4, Folder 98)
    - Richwood: Richwood Missionary Baptist Church, 1920 (Box 4, Folder 99)
    - Richwood: Richwood, Tennessee, 1909-1994 (Box 4, Folder 100)
    - Richwood: Richwood School, undated (Box 4, Folder 101)
    - Happy Valley: Happy Valley, 1957-1997 (Box 4, Folder 102)
    - Happy Valley: Rasar Family, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 103)
    - Happy Valley: Chilogatie Creek, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 104)
    - Look Rock, Tennessee: Mount Lanier, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 105)
    - Look Rock: Look Rock, 1966-2000 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Look Rock: Caylor Gap Viaduct (2500'), 1993-2005 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Look Rock: Foothills Parkway, 1944-2002 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Gregory Bald: Gregory Bald (4949'), 1890-2005 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Gregory Bald: Great Bald (now Gregory Bald), 1937 (Box 5, Folder 5)